Guide to the Henry Seidel Canby Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Professional Correspondence, 1896-59; Series I; 3; (6 boxes)
  - Holding, Elizabeth Sauxay, 1926
  - Holt, Henry, 1920, 1925
  - Hook, Sidney, 1932-34
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1928
  - Hoptner, Jacob, [1920], 1925
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1912-43 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Houseman, Lawrence, 1916 Mar 4
  - House, Edward M., 1917-28
  - Howard, Sidney, 1936 Nov 9 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Howe, DeWolfe, M. A., 1930-34
  - Howell, William Dean, 1915 Nov 12
  - Huebsch, Benjamin W., 1943 Dec 7 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Hueffer, Violet, n.d.
  - Hull, Gordon, 1939 Sep 29
  - Hunt, Peter, 1934 Dec 19
  - Huntington, Ellsworth, 1936 May 26
  - Hurst, Fannie, 1935 Feb 21
  - Huxley, Aldous, 1925-33
  - "I" general, 1918-45 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - International Council of English, 1921-27, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 107-112)
    See also: Robert Bridges The Society for Pure English
  - Irwin, Inez Haynes, 1935 Feb 14 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - "J" general, 1909-35 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Jackson, Joseph Henry, 1936, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - James, E. O., 1936
  - James, Henry, 1912 Jun 5
  - Jammes, Francis, 1935 Apr 3
  - Jarrett, Cora, 1936
  - Jastrow, Joseph, 1927-34, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Jászi, Oscar, 1930
  - Jeffers, Robinson, 1931 Feb 12
  - Jessup, Alexander, 1909-20 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Jewett, Sarah Orne, n.y. Jul 14
  - Johnson, James Weldon, 1936 Sep 14
  - Johnson, Henrietta Sherwood, 1936
  - Johnson, Mary, 1913, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1910
  - Jones, Eliot, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1936
  - Joyce, James, 1937 Jun 30
  - Jung, Carl G., 1926 Jun 14
  - Junior Red Cross, 1918 Oct 25
  - Jusserand, J. J. (Jean Jules), [19]09 Nov 5
  - "K" general, 1918-59 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Kallen, H. M., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Kaufman, George S., n.y. Nov 10
  - Kennedy, Constance Lindsay, 1921-22, n.d.
  - Kennedy, Raymond, 1927, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1930 Nov 15
  - Kern, Paul J., 1949
  - Keyserling, Count Hermann, 1924 Oct 15
  - Kipling, Rudyard, 1909-18 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1936 Jan 13
  - Koopman, Louise Osgood, 1933-47
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1936 Apr 7
  - Kunitz, Stanley J., 1936 Jan 4
  - "La" general, 1911-39 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - "Lb-Li" general, 1911-39 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - "Lj-Lz" general, 1918-47 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - La Farge, Christopher, 1939 Jan 25 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - La Follette, Suzanne, 1934
  - La Guardia, Fiorello, 1936 Nov 23
  - Laing, Alexander, 1934-36
  - Lamont, Thomas W., 1934-36 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Laski, Harold J., [19]31 May 10
  - Lawrence, D. H., 1923 Sep 1
  - Le maitre, Jules, [19]28 Nov 11
  - Leach, Henry G., 1932-36
  - Lenormand, H. R., 1934 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Lewis, Lloyd, 1936 Dec 1
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1925-36, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1928 Sep 14
  - Levy, Melvin P., 1930
  - Lindsay, Elizabeth, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Lindsay, Vachel, 1913-23
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Little, C. C., 1930
  - Lockridge, Ross, Jr., 1947-48
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1922 Oct 17
  - Lounsbury, Thomas R., 1908 Nov 11 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Low, Will H., 1930
  - Lowell, Amy, 1922, 1924
  - Luce, Henry, 1942, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Lynd, Robert S., 1930-32
  - "Ma" general, 1908-59 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - "Mb-Mi" general, 1914-45 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - "Mj-Mz" general, 1938-35 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - MacCarthy, Desmond, 1928-30, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - McCord, David, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - McCraken, Harold, 1930
  - MacCraken, Harold N., 1918, n.d.
  - McDermott, Edward, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - MacDonagh, Donagh, 1939
  - MacDonald, William, 1930, 1932
  - MacKenzie, Compton, 1915-16 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - MacLeod, Norman, 1936
  - The Macmillan Company, 1910-51 (Box 4, Folder 142-143)
  - MacNeill, Eoin, 1918 Apr 5 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Malone, Dumas, 1930, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Mamet, Louis, 1935-36, n.d.
  - Mann, Thomas, 1934-51
  - Marble, Annie Russell, 1930 Jan 11 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Marble, Charles F., 1937 Sep 2
  - Maritain, Jacques, 1934 Nov 11
  - Markham, Edwin, 1913 Apr 15
  - Marquis, Don, 1926, 1934
  - Marquand, J. P., 1948 Jan 23
  - Masefield, John, 1913, n.d.
  - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1922, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Mather, Frank Jewett, Jr., 1934-36
  - Matthews, Brander, 1902-13
  - Mattingly, Garrett, 1930, 1932, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Maurois, André, 1934, 1940, n.d.
  - Means, Philip Ainsworth, 1932
  - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1928-42, n.d.
  - Meneely, A. Howard, 1930-36
  - Merrill, Charles E., 1935, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Meyer, Leo J., 1929
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Monaghan, Frank, 1930
  - Moore, Marianne, 1949 Apr 26
  - Moore, Merrill, 1930
  - Morley, Christopher, 1923-43, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Morley, Felix, 1929-32 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Morris, Harrison, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Morris, Lawrence S., 1917
  - Morritt, Fred G., 1949
  - Mortimer, Raymond, 1933-34 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1929-32
  - Murray, Elizabeth, 1930
  - "N" general, 1912-59 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - National Labor War Board, 1918 Oct 16 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1930-43
  - Nicholson, Harold, 1933 Dec 30
  - Nicholson, Meredith, 1915
  - Nock, Albert Jay, 1930, 1934
  - Nock, Arthur, 1934, n.d.
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1936 Jan 30 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - New York Telegram, 1947, 1949
  - "O" general, 1916-51 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Obolensky, Prince Nicolas, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - O'Brien, Justin, 1938-39
  - O'Casey, Sean, 1934 Dec 8
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1928, 1934
  - Ould, Hermon, 1932-35 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Oliver, Edith, 1930 May 12
  - "Pa" general, 1912-45 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - "Pb-Pz" general, 1910-51 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - P.E.N. Club-Buenos Aires, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Pan American Union, 1936
  - Partridge, Bellamy, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1918-36 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Plunkett, Horace, 1918-19, n.d.
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1943 Jun 15
  - Pound, Ezra, 1920-39, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Powys, Llewelyn, 1927-32, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Priestly, J. B., 1927, 1946, n.d.
  - Prokosch, Frederic, n.d.
  - Public Ledger, 1916, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Putnam, Samuel, 1930
  - "Q" general, 1916, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - "Ra-Ri" general, 1911-36 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - "Rj-Rz" general, 1909-58 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Rackham, Arthur, [19]30 Oct 14 (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1933 Dec 19
  - Rascoe, Burton, 1933 Apr 19
  - Repplier, Agnes, 1922-23
  - Richards, Ivor Armstrong, 1931 Oct 24
  - Ridge, Lola, 1928-30, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Ritchie, Anne, n.y. Nov 14
  - Robins, Elizabeth, 1918-30
  - Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt, 1928 Oct 29 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1923, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Robinson, Ted, 1937
  - Rolland, Roamin, 1917 Nov 23
  - Rollins, Carl P., 1937, n.d.
  - Romains, Jules, 1936 May 29
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1942, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (secretary), 1932, 1936
  - Roosevelt, Kermit, 1934 Aug 16
  - Root, Elihu, 1935 Apr 2
  - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1939 Aug 20
  - Rothman, Nathan L., 1937, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Rourke, Constance, 1931-37
  - Rusk, R. L., 1937
  - Russell, A. E. [George], 1918, 1935
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1928 Apr 30
  - "Sa-Sc" general, 1914-59 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - "Se-Sm" general, 1911-45 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - "Sn-Sq" general, 1910-43 (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - "Sr-Sz" general, 1920-51 (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Sandoz, Mari, 1936 Jan 22 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Santayana, George, 1930-36
  - Sassoon, Siegfried, [19]29 Apr 24
  - Schelling, Felix, 1909 Oct 1
  - Schmalhausen, Samuel D., 1930-32
  - [Schmidt], Bernard H., 1930 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Schneider, Isidor, 1934 Apr 23
  - Schucht, Elisabeth, 1938
  - Scott, Donald, 1920 Feb 209 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Scott, Evelyn, 1934
  - Scoville, Samuel, Jr., 1922, 1929
  - Seal, Thomas, 1892-93
  - Sedgewick, Ellery, 1917, 1927
  - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley, n.y Feb 1, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1930-46
  - Seymour, George Dudley, 1922 Apr ?
  - Sforza, Carlo conte, [19]28 Apr 9 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Shanks, Lewis Piaget, [19]27 Jun 28
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1918, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Shepard, Odell, 1936-39
  - Sherman, Stuart P. and Ruth, 1924, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Simonson, Lee, 1931
  - Sinclair, May, 1918, n.d.
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1947 May 3
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1927-49 (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Sitwell, Osbert, 1926 Feb 6
  - Skinner, Constance Lindsay
  - Smith, A. W., 1930-36 (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Smith, Clara, 1918
  - Smith, Harrison, 1920 Mar 16
  - Smith, Norman Kemp, 1917 Oct 12
  - Smith, T. R., 1917
  - Smyser, William Leon, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Snelling, Paula, 1937
  - Society for Pure English, 1930, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    See also: Arthur James Balfour Lord Balfour Robert Bridges International Council of English
  - Spiller, Robert E., 1930-51 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Sprague, Harriet S., n.y. Jun 24
  - Starke, Aubrey H., 1937
  - Starrett, Vincent, 1931 Oct 26 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Stegner, Wallace, 1939
  - Stein, Gertrude, n.d.
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren, 1937
  - Stevens, James, 1920 May 12 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Stevens, William O., 1921-22, n.d.
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1900 Jun 30
  - Stopler, Toni, 1939
  - Strachey, Lytton, 1929-30
  - Strand, Paul, 1931 Nov 13
  - Strong, Phil, 1937
  - Stuart, Jesse, 1939-43 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Sullivan, Mark, 1926-32
  - Swinnerton, Frank, 1922[?]-23
  - "T" general, 1909-43 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Taft, William Howard, 1917-18 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Taggard, Genevieve, 1938 Nov 6
  - Tarkington, Booth, 1915-33
  - Thayer, Tiffany, 1939 Nov 2 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Thoma, Richard, 1936
  - Thomas, Norman, 1930-58
  - Thomas, Ralph B. and Vera, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Thomas, T. H., 1930, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Thompson, K., n.d.
  - Thornton, Hugh C., 1918 (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - Thurber, James, 1937-45, n.d.
  - Thurston, Carl, 1931
  - Tilton, Cecil G., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - The Times (London, England), 1918
  - Tobsoj, Signe, 1938
  - Todd, Mabel Loomis, 1930
  - Toklas, Alice B., n.y. Nov 14
  - Toller, Ernst, 1933-39 (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Tomlinson, H. M., 1925-50
  - Trevelyan, George MaCaulay, 1924 Apr 14 (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - "U" general, 1917-45 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - Underhill, Sophie K., 1934-35 (Box 6, Folder 207)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1930-37, n.d.
  - United States. Office of War Information, 1945-47
  - "V" general, 1927-60 (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - Van Benthuysen, Boyd, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Van Dyke, Henry, [19]02, 1918
  - Van Doren, Carl, 1931 Aug 20
  - Van Loon, Hendrick Willem, [1939] Sep 9
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1922 Mar 3
  - Van Vilsor, V. V., 1942
  - Villard, Oswald, Garrison, 1934-46, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - "W" general, 1900-45 (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Wagner, Robert F., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - Waldman, Milton, 1935, n.d.
  - Wall, John R., 1910
  - Walton, J. McLean, 1913 Dec 22
  - Ward, C. H., n.y. Nov 10 (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - Ward, Christopher, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Ward, Estelle Frances, 1938
  - Wecter, Dixon, 1943
  - The Week-end Review, 1930
  - Weeks, Edward, 1936 Apr 14
  - Wells, Carolyn, 1938 Sep 27 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Wells, E. W., 1909 Dec 7
  - Wells, H. G., 1924-36, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Wells, Marjorie, 1934, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - Went, Stanley, 1930, 1936
  - Wescott, Glenway (transcript), 1950 Jun 8 (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - West, Rebecca, 192?, n.d.
  - Wharton, Edith, 1922, 1933
  - White, William A., 1927-38 (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - White William, 1938 Jun 10
  - Widdemer, Margaret, 1924, 1932, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1924-49
  - Wilkie, Wendell L., 1943 Jun 10
  - Wilson, Francis G., 1934
  - Wilson, Woodrow and Edith Bolling, 1917-25 (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - Wolfe, Thomas, 1936-37
  - Wood, Eric Fisher, 1917-18 (Box 6, Folder 222)
  - Woodbridge, Homer E., 1930, 1935
  - Woodruff, Edward Lyndon, 1900, 1908
  - Woods, Margaret L., n.d.
  - Woollicott, Alexander, 1934 Oct 30
  - Woolsey, John M., 1933 Dec 6
  - Woolf, Virginia, 1928
  - Wylie, Elinor, [19]27
  - Yale University, 1900-58 (Box 6, Folder 223)
    See also: James Rowland Angell Tucker Brooks Jerome Davis Dr. Theodore M. Greene A. Whitney Griswold Arthur Twining Hadley Ellsworth Huntington William Lyon Phelps Charles Seymour Anson Phelps Stokes, Jr.
  - The Youth's Companion, 1896 May 29 (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1934 Dec 17 (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - Zukofsky, Louis, 1932 Apr 15
  - Unidentified, 1900-51 (Box 6, Folder 226-229)
- Family Correspondence, 1897-45; Series II; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series II, Family Correspondence (Boxes 7-12) is alphabetically arranged by author, and therein chronologically.
  - Canby, Edward Tatnall and Ella Augusta Seidel, 1897-99 (Box 7, Folder 230-232)
  - Canby, Edward Tatnall and Ella Augusta Seidel, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 233-238)
  - Canby, Edward Tatnall and Ella Augusta Seidel, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 239-244)
  - Canby, Edward Tatnall and Ella Augusta Seidel, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 245-247)
  - Canby, Edward Tatnall and Ella Augusta Seidel, 1903, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 248-249)
  - Canby, Edward Tatnall and Ella Augusta Seidel (Box 7, Folder 250)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 251-257)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 258)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1918 Jan-Mar (Box 8, Folder 259-263)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1918 Apr-Jun (Box 8, Folder 264-268)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1918 Jun-Jul (Box 9, Folder 269-272)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, [1918] (Box 9, Folder 273)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 274)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 275-278)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 279)
  - Canby, Marion (Kit), 1898-99 (Box 9, Folder 280-282)
  - Canby, Marion (Kit), 1900 (Box 9, Folder 283-285)
  - Canby, Marion (Kit), 1901-03, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 286-290)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1906 Mar-Apr (Box 10, Folder 291-296)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1906 May (Box 10, Folder 297-303)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1906 Jun-Sep (Box 10, Folder 304-309)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1906 Oct (Box 11, Folder 310-313)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1906 Nov (Box 11, Folder 314-316)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1906 Dec (Box 11, Folder 317-319)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1907 Jan (Box 11, Folder 320-322)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1907 Feb (Box 11, Folder 323-326)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1907 Mar (Box 12, Folder 327-330)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1907 Apr (Box 12, Folder 331-333)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1907 May (Box 12, Folder 334-337)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1907 Jun (Box 12, Folder 338-339)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1911-12 (Box 12, Folder 340)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1918 (Box 12, Folder 341)
  - Canby, Marion Ponsonby (Lady), 1926, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 342)
- Writings, 1879-58; Series III; 12; (19 boxes)
  Series III, Writings (Boxes 13-31), is divided into three subseries: Books, which is arranged alphabetically by title; Shorter Works, which is arranged alphabetically by literary genre and within that alphabetically by title; and Writings of Others, which is arranged alphabetically by author. Works without an identified author are arranged alphabetically by title at the end of Writings of Others.
  - BOOKS
    - Bibliography [of books by Henry Seidel Canby]
      - July 1, 1920 - June 30, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 343)
    - The Age of Confidence
      - Advertisement, [ca. 1934] (Box 13, Folder 344)
      - Book reviews, 1934-35, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 345-346)
    - Alma Mater
      - Draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 347-351)
      - Advertisement and order form, [ca. 1936] (Box 13, Folder 352)
      - Book reviews, 1936, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 353)
    - American Estimates
      - Book reviews, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 354)
    - American Memoir
      - Draft, typescript and proof, corrected (Box 13, Folder 355-359)
      - Draft, typescript and proof, corrected (Box 14, Folder 360-368)
      - Reader's reports, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 369)
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 370)
      - Book reviews, 1947, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 371)
    - Antony and Cleopatra
      - Draft, typescript, printed version, corrected, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 372-374)
      - Index cards: footnotes to text, [ca. 1920] (Box 15, Folder 375)
    - Better Writing
      - Book reviews, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 376)
    - The Book of the Short Story
      - Contract, 1903 Apr 8 (Box 16, Folder 377)
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 378)
      - Book reviews, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 379)
    - The Brandywine
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 380)
      - Book reviews, 1941, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 381)
    - Classic Americans
      - Book reviews, 1931, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 382)
    - College Sons and College Fathers
      - Book reviews, 1915-16, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 383)
    - Definitions: First Series
      - Book reviews, 1922-23, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 384)
    - Definitions: Second Series
      - Publicity, 1924 Sep 7 (Box 16, Folder 385)
      - Book reviews, 1924-25, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 386)
    - Education by Violence
      - Book reviews, 1919-20, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 387-388)
    - Elements of Composition
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 389)
    - English Composition in Theory and Practice
      - Book reviews, 1910-13, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 390)
    - Everyday Americans
      - Book reviews, 1920-23, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 391)
    - Facts, Thought and Imagination
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 392)
    - Family History
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, ca. 1945 (Box 16, Folder 393-394)
      - Book reviews, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 395)
    - Literary History of the United States
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 396)
      - Summary outline, 1944 Jul 15 (Box 18, Folder 397)
      - Book reviews, 1948, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 398)
    - Memoir of a Writer Between Two Wars
      - Second draft, holograph, typescript, corrected (incomplete) (Box 18, Folder 399-405)
    - A New Land Speaking
      - Book reviews, ca. 1946 (Box 18, Folder 406)
    - Our House
      - Introduction: draft, holograph, corrected (Box 18, Folder 407)
      - Book I
        - Chapter 1, "Chicken and Waffles": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 18, Folder 408)
        - Chapter 2, "The 'Rock'": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 409)
        - Chapter 3, "Home": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 410)
        - Chapter 4, "Compromise": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 411)
        - Chapter 5, "Work": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 412)
        - Chapter 6, "Intermezzo": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 413)
        - Chapter 7, "Pastorale": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 414)
        - Chapter 8, "Crisis": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 415)
        - Chapter 9, "Release": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 416)
      - Book II
        - Chapter 1, "Johnny Bolt": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 417)
        - Chapter 2, "New York": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 418)
        - Chapter 3, "Facts" [published as "Search and Research"]: draft, holograph, corrected (Box 18, Folder 419)
        - Chapter 4, "The Rocket": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 420)
        - Chapter 5, "Mary Doone": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 421)
        - Chapter 6, "Life for Art's Sake": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 422)
        - Chapter 7, "The Real Thing": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 423)
        - Chapter 8, "Crowfoot": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 424)
        - Chapter 9, "Spoon or Straw": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 425)
        - Chapter 10, "Not Wounded, Sire,-- But Dead": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 18, Folder 426)
        - Chapter 11, "Terra Incognita": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 427)
      - Book III
        - Chapter 1, "The Lull": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 428)
        - Chapter 2, "The Plunge": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 429)
        - Chapter 3, "Struggle": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 430)
      - Book IV
        - Chapter 1, "The Quick or the Dead": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 431)
        - Chapter 2, "The God of Cash": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 432)
        - Chapter 3, "The Mysterious Stranger": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 433)
        - Chapter 4, "Sumach, Cedar, and Bay": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 19, Folder 434)
        - Chapter 5, "Doubt": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 435)
        - Chapter 6, "Dawn": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 19, Folder 436)
        - Chapter 8, "Millingtown at Last": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 437)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 438)
      - Advertisements, ca. 1919 (Box 19, Folder 439)
      - Book reviews, 1919, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 440-443)
    - The People Called Quakers
      - Book reviews, 1912 Nov (Box 19, Folder 444)
    - Saturday Papers
      - Book reviews, 1922 Feb 5 (Box 19, Folder 445)
    - Seven Years' Harvest
      - Book reviews, 1936, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 446)
    - The Short Story in English
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 447)
      - Book reviews, 1909-10, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 448)
      - Royalty statement (includes royalty payments for War Aims and Ideals ), 1925 Jan 31 (Box 19, Folder 449)
    - A Study of the Short Story
      - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 450)
    - Thoreau: A Biography
      - Research materials, 1879-1951 (Box 19, Folder 451-455)
      - Research materials, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 456)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 457-466)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 467-472)
      - Page proofs, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 473-474)
      - Advertisements, ca. 1939 (Box 21, Folder 475)
        See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 914
      - Book reviews, 1939, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 476)
    - Turn West, Turn East: Mark Twain and Henry James
      - Photographs
        - Twain, Mark, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 477)
        - James, Henry, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 478)
      - Research materials, 1939-48, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 479)
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 480)
      - Draft A
        - Introduction: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 481)
        - Chapter 3, "Mark Twain Arrives": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 23, Folder 482)
        - Chapter 4, "James Makes His First (and last) Popular Success": holograph, corrected (Box 23, Folder 483)
        - Chapter 5, "Twain Finds a Treasure in Hannibal": holograph, corrected (Box 23, Folder 484)
        - Chapter 6, "Henry Writes His First Great Novel": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 485)
        - Chapter 7, "Machine-Age Yankee": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 486)
        - Chapter 8, "Varieties of Feminine Experience": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 487)
        - Chapter 9, "Mark Twain Watches Too Many Baskets": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 488)